UZIAS RIVERA

FRONT END DEVELOPER

CONTACT

■ uziasrivera@gmail.com

uziasrivera.com

4 6267746838

♀ Los Angeles, CA

in uziasrivera

Q uziasr

SUMMARY

Front End Developer with a passion for producing creative solutions while prioritizing user experience.

Knowledgeable in developing user interfaces, interactive applications, data analysis, RESTful API's, state management systems and highly skilled working in teams inside and outside of tech.

SKILLS

FRONTEND

JavaScript

React

Redux

JWT

Angular

TypeScript

HTML

CSS

LESS

Material-UI

Semantic-UI

BACKEND

Node.js

Express

SQL

SQLite Postgres

rosigie

Knex

Middleware

PROJECTS

Form Critic

A platform where people who exercise can get feedback on their form for the purpose of rectifying bad exercise habits and promoting wellness.

Node.js | Express | Knex | SQLite3 | React | Redux | Material UI

- Planned the site closely with an experienced personal trainer with many years in the industry
- Designed a normalized relational database using Knex
- Implemented authentication using JSON Web Tokens to allow users to edit and delete posts that belong to them
- Deployed a back end using Node.js and Express with various endpoints and middleware that support CRUD operations

Kickstarter Success

An application that determines the likelihood a Kickstarter post is to succeed by taking the title, summary, country, and monetary goal and returning a success percentage with the use of machine learning.

React | Redux | JavaScript | HTML | CSS

- Developed various functional components with React including register and login components with validators, in a team of web developers and data scientists.
- Used axios to send request to the API with the purpose of implementing CRUD functionality to application

EMPLOYMENT

Lambda Remote

Team Lead

Jan. 2020 to Current

- Managed a team of eight students in a manner that emulates a real work environment using the agile methodology
- Reviewed projects in one on one meetings and supplied students with technical support and provided additional resources to reassure their understanding of the concepts
- Led daily stand-ups that fostered a productive environment where diverse perspectives thrived and provided students with guidance for the week's material

Connect Our Kids

Remote Dec. 2019 to Feb. 2020

React Native Developer - Intern

- Developed a form to edit data for individuals and implemented yup to validate every field to enforce data integrity
- Created multiple actions using the existing redux state management system to connect components with state
- Communicated with the UX engineers to match the design of the app to their prototype

EDUCATION

Lambda

Aug. 2019 to Apr. 2020

Dec. 2018

Full Stack Web Development 2020

California State Polytechnic University, Pomona

Bachelors of Science Hospitality Management, Computer Information Systems Minor